

Luis Genesius iOS Engineer

Jakarta, Indonesia

in linkedin.com/in/luisgenesius



luis.huang321@gmail.com

Igenesius.github.io/portfolio



(+62) 82153795325

Summary

Luis Genesius is a computer science undergraduate student at Bina Nusantara University and also a passionate iOS Engineer who has published 2 apps to the App Store. In June 2021, Luis is one of the 350 students in the world that won WWDC 2021 Swift Student Challenge.

Achievements

- Won Worldwide Developer Conference (WWDC) 2021 Swift Student Challenge Scholarship
- Indosat Digital Camp (IDCamp) 2021 Scholarship to iOS Expert Certificate
- Apple Developer Academy Scholarship
- Excellent Achievements as a scholarship student mentor in BSLC

Skills

Technical Skills:

- iOS Development
- Xcode
- Swift
- SwiftUI
- UIKit
- Git
- Core Data
- Combine

Soft Skills:

- Problem Solving
- Communication
- Collaboration
- Fast Learner
- Ownership

Language Skills:

• Indonesia (Native) • English (Advance)

Education

Computer Science Undergraduate

Bina Nusantara University (Sep 2018 - Present) GPA 3.79/4.00

- · Specialty: Software Engineering
- Sub Specialty: Mobile Apps Development

Work Experience

iOS Engineer

Apple Developer Academy @ BINUS (Feb 2021 - Des 2021)

- Developed 5 apps with deadline period ranging from 1-3 months and 2 out of 5 apps are published to App Store
- Led engineering team two times to architecturing and building the projects
- Main task are develop app's core feature, research tech feasibility, solve engineering problems and publish apps to Testflight or App Store

Scholarship Student Mentor

Binus Student Learning Community (Sep 2019 - Jan 2020)

- Guide 7 fellow students in studying college subjects and help to prepare for mid exam and final exam
- Evaluate fellow students to provide appropriate strategies to help them study

Projects



a iOS photo editor app that helps micro & small online business owners to create social media photos easier and better

- Built and architectured the core UI foundation using SwiftUI
- Implemented GET and POST API, CoreML, Vision, and Combine
- Designed and built the Core Data model and the relationships
- Designed and implemented the business logic as a ViewModel

an iOS app that helps users easily create meal plans, integrate shopping lists, and track their groceries at home all at once.

- Led iOS Engineering team to designed the data model, developed and architectured the app
- · Built the UI using UIKit with XIB and worked with auto layout
- Built the watchOS companion app using SwiftUI and Watch Connectivity

If you want to know more about the projects Luis developed, you can go to his portfolio web or you can scan the QR Code:

